This paper is a companion to a GDC 2008 Lecture with the same title. It provides a brief overview of spherical harmonics (SH) and discusses several ways they can be used in interactive graphics and problems that might arise. In particular it focuses on the following issues: How to evaluate lighting models efficiently using SH, what “ringing” is and what you can do about it, efficient evaluation of SH products and where they might be used.
북방한계선(NLL)에 잡음이 불거질 때마다 생업인 어업과 관광 모두 지대한 타격을 입을 수밖에 없지만, 주민들에게 '군(軍) 얘기'는 쉬쉬할 수밖에 없는 금기의 영역이다.
鳩山由紀夫首相は１２日昼、米ワシントンで開かれる核安全保障サミット（１２～１３日）に出席するため、政府専用機で羽田空港を出発する。
据新华社电 搭载波兰总统卡钦斯基遗体的飞机11日下午抵达波兰首都华沙,代行总统职权的众议长科莫罗夫斯基、总理图斯克等政府要员以及卡钦斯基的亲属到机场迎接。
